Guide to the Constance D'Agosta Brooklyn Dodgers Collection CBHM.0001
Center for Brooklyn History
Constance D'Agosta Brooklyn Dodgers Collection
1947-2014
Center for Brooklyn History
CBHM.0001
8 Linear Feet in 5 legal document boxes, 3 record cartons, 4 flat boxes, and 2 oversize flat file folders.
This collection includes Brooklyn Dodgers memorabilia, clippings, ephemera, and photographs. Also included are the personal photographs and correspondence of Constance "Connie" D'Agosta, co-founder of the "Dodger Debs".
Arrangement
Series I: Clippings and Newsletters is arranged alphabetically by title where possible. Untitled items in this series are grouped by format with no chronological arrangement.
Series II: Correspondence and Advocacy is arranged chronologically.
Series III: Objects and Ephemera is arranged alphabetically.
Series IV: Prints and Photographs is grouped by size. Small photographs, baseball cards, and slides are in a single binder with no arrangement. Oversize prints are foldered together with no arrangement and plaques are boxed with no arrangement.
Series V: Publications are grouped by format and arranged chronologically.
Series VI: Audiovisual items are not arranged.
Historical Note
Baseball clubs were introduced to Kings County as early as the 1820s, with over 71 amateur teams playing in the county by 1851. Early prominent clubs included the Atlantics and the Ekfords, drawing players from the blue collar workforce and attracting thousands of fans to games played all over the borough. In 1883, Charles Byrne opened the Washington Park baseball field on 5th Avenue and 3rd Street in Park Slope and formed a team called the Brooklyn Grays. The team joined the American Association in 1884 and the National League in 1890, by which time they were known as the Bridegrooms.
In 1891 Washington Park burned down and the team was moved to Eastern Park, a 12,000 seat stadium in Brooklyn's Brownsville neighborhood. The team was still known as the Bridegrooms but picked up several nicknames including the Superbas and the Brooklyn Trolley Dodgers, named after borough residents who had to "dodge" oncoming electric trollies. In 1898 Byrne died and was succeeded by his assistant, Charlie Ebbets. By 1899 Ebbets gained majority control over the team and in 1912 moved them to Ebbets Field, a new 37,000 seat stadium in Flatbush. The team played and lost their first World Series game in 1916, in front of the largest crowd in baseball history. By 1920 the team was officially known as the Brooklyn Dodgers, but was also called the Daffiness Boys, a nickname reflective of their performance on the field and outrageous behavior of players and management. The death of Charlie Ebbets in 1925 left the team open to poor management and a series of disastrous trades that led to a drop in ticket sales and a field in need of repairs. Things began to turn around in 1938 when Leland MacPhail was brought in as General Manager. MacPhail got rid of the Daffiness Boys and replaced them with some of the Dodgers' most iconic players, including Pee Wee Reese and Pete Reiser.
When the U.S. entered World War II MacPhail and several players enlisted. Branch Rickey was brought in from St. Louis as the new General Manager. In 1947 he signed Jackie Robinson, the first black man to play on a major league baseball team. The 1947 season kicked off an era often called the "glory days" with star players including Roy Campanella, Duke Snider and Gil Hodges. Brooklyn supported their team with steady game attendance, merchandise sales and their own fight song, "Follow the Dodgers." After years of close-calls and near-misses the team finally captured a World Series title in the 1955 season.
After 43 years Ebbets Field was in a state of disrepair and team owner Walter O'Malley began to make plans for a new stadium in Brooklyn. O'Malley's plan for a city subsidized stadium at the intersection of Flatbush and Atlantic Avenue that would provide more seats, parking and access to public transportation was rejected by Robert Moses, who proposed an alternative location in Queens, the eventual site of Shea Stadium. O'Malley began negotiations with the city of Los Angeles, which promised a growing market and space for a new stadium. The National League authorized the move on May 28, 1957 and the Los Angeles Dodgers played their first game on April 18, 1958.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection may only be used in the library and is not available through interlibrary loan. Requests to view the collection must be made at least 48 hours in advance of visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was donated in part to the Brooklyn Historical Society in 2018. An additional donation was given to the Brooklyn Collection in 2019. Both gifts were provided by Joseph and Barbara D'Agosta.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of Brooklyn Dodgers memorabilia and publications collected by Constance "Connie" D'Agosta. Clippings cover baseball games, player news, and the team's move to Los Angeles. Later articles cover the deaths of various players, news about Hall of Fame inductees, and short histories of the team. Scrapbooks include clippings, photographs, and ephemera. Newsletters include content created by D'Agosta for the "Dodger Debs" and the Clem Labine / Johnny Podres Fan Club.
Ephemera and objects include various Dodgers and player memorabilia, including Ebbets Field models, game tickets, game programs, pins, and signed baseballs. The bulk of the photographs date 1950-1970 and show D'Agosta and friends attending games and posing with team members. Pitcher Clem Labine is heavily featured, with several of his photographs signed. Prints and plaques are commemorative. Publications include official Dodgers yearbooks and books concerning the history of the Dodgers and biographies of several players. Correspondence and clippings found in book pages have not been removed.
Correspondence is D'Agosta's personal correspondence to friends and Dodgers contacts; and print outs from the Baseball Fever message board, where D'Agosta was a moderator. Also included is a collection of letters to Clem Labine from fans, requesting signatures and sending general greetings. Included in this series is notes, research, and correspondence regarding D'Agosta's work with Community Board 10 to name Duke Snider Place and her work planning the 50th anniversary celebration of the Dodgers' 1955 World Series win.
Separated Materials
Books separated from the Constance D'Agosta Brooklyn Dodgers Collection and added to the Center for Brooklyn History non-circulating book collection. Consult the Brooklyn Public Library catalog for location.
Robins, Sharon. Promises Kept. Scholastic Press, 2004.
Enders, Eric. Ballparks Now and Then. Thunder Bay Press, 2002.
Langill, Mark. Dodger Stadium. Arcadia Publishing, 2004.
Nordell, John R. Brooklyn Dodgers, The Last Great Pennant Drive, 1957. Tribute Books, 2007.
Parker, Robert B. Double Play. G.P. Putnam's Sons, 2004.
Langill, Mark. Dodgertown. Arcadia Publishing, 2004.
Bavasi, Buzzie. Off the Record. Contemporary Books, Inc., 1987.
Elliott, Richard. Clem Labine, Always a Dodger. Page Publishing, 2015.
Bennett, Bob; Bennet, John; Bennett, Robert S. Johnny Podres, Brooklyn's Only Yankee Killer. Author House, 2005.
Related Materials
Al Todres Brooklyn Dodgers Collection BCMS.0052
Brooklyn Dodgers collection ARC.297
Brooklyn Dodgers team photographs V1987.019
Collection of Brooklyn Dodgers photographic portraits ARC.265
Larry Trapani Brooklyn Dodgers collection 2005.037
Stanley Person Baseball Collection BCMS.0065
Walter O'Malley Brooklyn Dodgers records ARC.294
Biographical Note
Constance "Connie" D'Agosta was a lifelong Dodgers fan and one of the co-founders of the "Dodger Debs," a fan club that met to attend games, photograph players, write cheers and produce newsletters. She maintained friendships and correspondence with several players, including Clem Labine, Johnny Podres, Pee Wee Reese, and Dick Williams. In 2005 she co-chaired the event celebrating the 50th anniversary of the 1955 World Series Championship.
Brooklyn Dodgers (Baseball team); Baseball players |z New York (State) |z New York; Baseball fans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Baseballs (ball); Scrapbooks; Ephemera; Clippings (information artifacts); Ebbets Field (New York, N.Y.); Sports writing; Sports -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Photographic prints; Memorabilia; Baseball teams |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Series I: Clippings and Newsletters
  - Press Releases, 2003-2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Brooklyn Bums Newsletter, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn Dodgers Baseball Hall of Fame Newsletter, 1993-2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dodgers Alumni Newsletter, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dodger Debs Newsletter, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Line Drives Newsletter, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pitchin' Curves With Clem and Johnny, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Baseball Digest Magazine, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baseball Magazine, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Baseball Pictoral Magazine, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Commemorative Magazines, 1966, circa 1975, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Daily News Sports Century, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sports Illustrated, 1957, 1999, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sport Magazine, 1957, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sport Life Magazine, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, circa 1955-2012 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Scrapbook, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook Access Copy, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1950-1953 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook Access Copy, 1950-1953 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook Access Copy, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Clem Labine Scrapbook, 1951-1956 (Box 5)
  - Clem Labine Scrapbook Access Copy, 1951-1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Series II: Correspondence and Advocacy
  - Baseball Fever Message Board, 2003-2009 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1967, 1971-1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2001-2009 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2010-2014 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Notes, circa 2000-2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fanmail to Clem Labine, 1987-2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 50th Anniversary Event Planning, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Duke Snider Place Proposal, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Series III: Objects and Ephemera
  - Brooklyn Historical Society Exhibit Brochures, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bumperstickers, Magnets, circa 2000 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Calendars, 1986-1987, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Card, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Commemorative Stamp, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dodgers Chants, circa 1957-2010 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Funeral Program, Jackie Robinson, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Game Programs, 1950-1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Game Schedule, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Game Tickets, 1955-1966 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Game Tickets - Rainchecks, 1955-1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Invitations, 1990, 2003-2005 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - The Jackie Robinson / Pee Wee Reese Project, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Menu, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Old Timers Day Programs, 1962-1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Petition, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Prayer Card, Gil Hodges, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Constance D'Agosta's Writing, circa 1957-2010 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Certificate, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Coins, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - License Plate Frame, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Mouse Pads, circa 1995 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Patches, Circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Pins, circa 1955-2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Signs, Pennant, 1955, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Ebbets Field Puzzle, 1994 (Box 10)
  - 11 Baseballs, 1955-1971 (Box 11)
  - Soil From Dodgertown, 2008 (Box 11)
  - Ebbets Field Music Box, circa 2000 (Box 11)
  - Wood Sign with Stand, circa 1980 (Box 11)
  - Wood from Ebbets Field in Plastic Display Case, circa 1955 (Box 11)
  - World Champions Stamp, circa 1955 (Box 11)
  - Plastic Los Angeles Dodgers Helmet, circa 1970 (Box 11)
  - Miniature Louisville Slugger Baseball Bat, 1957 (Box 11)
  - Shot Glass, circa 2000 (Box 12)
  - Commemorative Ceramic Mug, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Two Ebbets Field Models, circa 2000 (Box 12)
  - Ebbets Field Model Paperwork, circa 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Two Dodgers Pennants, circa 1955 (Flat file folder CBHM.0001)
- Series IV: Prints and Photographs
  - Photographs, Slides, and Baseball Cards, circa 1950-2007 (Box 6, Binder 1)
  - Oversize Prints, circa 1980-2005 (Cabinet Morgue Flat File 1, Drawer 10)
  - Oversize Prints, circa 1955-1990 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Seagram's Gil Hodges Commemorative Framed Print, circa 1970 (Box 7, Object 1-2)
  - World Champions Plaque, circa 2000 (Box 8, Object 1)
  - Clem Labine Plaque, signed, circa 2000 (Box 8, Object 2)
  - Clem Labine Plaque, signed, circa 2000 (Box 8, Object 3)
  - World Champions Plaque, circa 2000 (Box 8, Object 4)
  - Ebbets Field Plaque, 1994 (Box 8, Object 5)
  - Ebbets Field Print, circa 2000 (Flat file folder CBHM.0001)
- Series V: Publications
  - Dodgers Yearbooks, 1949-1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dodgers Yearbooks, 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Books, 1954-2010 (Box 9, Object 1-19)
- Series VI: Audiovisual
  - Dodgers Programs, VHS, 1947, 1998, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Vinyl Records, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Vinyl Records, 1957-1958, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)